(Watch on www.dramacool.club Support Admin)
(Watch on www.dramacool.club Support Admin)
PERFECT CROWN
PERFECT CROWN
THIS IS A WORK OF FICTION
THIS IS A WORK OF FICTION
CHILD ACTORS AND ANIMALS WERE FILMED SAFELY
CHILD ACTORS AND ANIMALS WERE FILMED SAFELY
PERFECT CROWN
PERFECT CROWN
An accident?
An accident?
What have you heard exactly?
What have you heard exactly?
Only that there was a collision.
Only that there was a collision.
I need to be there.
I need to be there.
Do not just stand there.
Do not just stand there.
Prepare to leave at once!
Prepare to leave at once!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Yes, Your Majesty.
THE ROYAL SEOUL HOSPITAL
THE ROYAL SEOUL HOSPITAL
How did this happen?
How did this happen?
What about His Majesty?
What about His Majesty?
Was there an attack on His Majesty's life?
Was there an attack on His Majesty's life?
Say something!
Say something!
Please calm down, Your Majesty.
Please calm down, Your Majesty.
His scans reveal no fractures or internal injuries.
His scans reveal no fractures or internal injuries.
Just some minor bruising.
Just some minor bruising.
And the Grand Prince?
And the Grand Prince?
I heard he was at the scene as well.
I heard he was at the scene as well.
Is he all right?
Is he all right?
He is in surgery.
He is in surgery.
It appears his left shoulder bore much of the impact.
It appears his left shoulder bore much of the impact.
It seems he has done everything in his power to stop the car.
It seems he has done everything in his power to stop the car.
Prime Minister Min.
Prime Minister Min.
May I have a word?
May I have a word?
Photos of the accident have spread on social media.
Photos of the accident have spread on social media.
Her conspicuous vehicle didn't help.
Her conspicuous vehicle didn't help.
How is Ms. Seong doing?
How is Ms. Seong doing?
She's still unconscious, but the scans have come back clean.
She's still unconscious, but the scans have come back clean.
Hmm. Are photos of the escort vehicles also circulating?
Hmm. Are photos of the escort vehicles also circulating?
No. They were some distance away from the scene,
No. They were some distance away from the scene,
and we're removing them as they appear.
and we're removing them as they appear.
That should be enough.
That should be enough.
Pushing too hard will raise--
Pushing too hard will raise--
What did you just say?
What did you just say?
What does Ms. Seong Huiju have to do with any of this?
What does Ms. Seong Huiju have to do with any of this?
Are you saying the vehicle involved,
Are you saying the vehicle involved,
the one His Majesty was in, belongs to that woman?
the one His Majesty was in, belongs to that woman?
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
Where are you going?
Where are you going?
Must I report such things to you?
Must I report such things to you?
The wise decision
The wise decision
would be to not go anywhere.
would be to not go anywhere.
The people know Ms. Seong's vehicle was involved.
The people know Ms. Seong's vehicle was involved.
So?
So?
"His Majesty was in that car
"His Majesty was in that car
and the Grand Prince caused an accident to save him,
and the Grand Prince caused an accident to save him,
racking up countless traffic violations and substantial damage in the process."
racking up countless traffic violations and substantial damage in the process."
If word of this got out,
If word of this got out,
all of this could be blamed
all of this could be blamed
on the young king.
on the young king.
Prime Minister Min.
Prime Minister Min.
I am merely stating that it could lead
I am merely stating that it could lead
to such dire conclusions.
to such dire conclusions.
Are you trying to protect that maiden?
Are you trying to protect that maiden?
I am trying to protect the Crown.
I am trying to protect the Crown.
OPERATING CENTER
OPERATING CENTER
LEE IN RECOVERY
LEE IN RECOVERY
The surgery went well.
The surgery went well.
The anesthesia has just worn off,
The anesthesia has just worn off,
so he should be able to go up to his room in about an hour.
so he should be able to go up to his room in about an hour.
What about any lasting effects?
What about any lasting effects?
I heard it can be difficult to use your arm after shoulder surgery.
I heard it can be difficult to use your arm after shoulder surgery.
The surgery wasn't due to a fracture or a chronic condition,
The surgery wasn't due to a fracture or a chronic condition,
so that is unlikely.
so that is unlikely.
-No need to worry. -Thank you.
-No need to worry. -Thank you.
-Thank you, Doctor.
-Thank you, Doctor.
Thank goodness.
Thank goodness.
-That's a relief. -Yes.
-That's a relief. -Yes.
Let's increase security on the floor Ms. Seong is on.
Let's increase security on the floor Ms. Seong is on.
-Send people from our office. -Yes, sir.
-Send people from our office. -Yes, sir.
Let me know as soon as she wakes up.
Beri tahu saya segera setelah dia bangun.
Yes, sir.
Baik, Pak.
SEONG HUIJU
SEONG HUIJU
Ms. Seong.
Ibu Seong.
Your Majesty?
Yang Mulia?
Are you awake?
Apakah kamu sudah bangun?
Your Majesty! Are you all right?
Yang Mulia! Apakah Anda baik-baik saja?
Is anything broken?
Apakah ada yang rusak?
I am sorry.
Saya minta maaf.
This all happened because I insisted on a drive.
Semua ini terjadi karena saya bersikeras untuk berkendara.
Not at all.
Sama sekali tidak.
Your Majesty and I are both fine.
Yang Mulia dan saya sama-sama baik-baik saja.
Wait, His Royal Highness.
Tunggu, Yang Mulia.
Where is the Grand Prince? Is he here as well?
Di mana Pangeran Agung? Apakah dia juga ada di sini?
Do not worry.
Jangan kuatir.
Uncle did not faint.
Paman tidak pingsan.
He even went into the operating room without crying.
Dia bahkan masuk ke ruang operasi tanpa menangis.
The operating room?
Ruang operasi?
He's having surgery?
Dia akan menjalani operasi?
Would you like some water?
Apakah Anda ingin air minum?
Is the surgery over?
Apakah operasinya sudah selesai?
Are you okay?
Apakah kamu baik-baik saja?
I mean, what were you thinking, jumping in there?
Maksudku, apa yang kau pikirkan, tiba-tiba masuk ke sana?
Are you insane?
Apakah kamu gila?
Ms. Seong, His Royal Highness has just woken up from the anesthesia…
Nona Seong, Yang Mulia Pangeran baru saja sadar dari pengaruh anestesi…
-You can't just-- -Hold on.
-Kamu tidak bisa begitu saja-- -Tunggu dulu.
You even hurt your face?
Kamu sampai melukai wajahmu?
When that's all you have going for you?
Ketika hanya itu yang kamu miliki?
Oh, no.
Oh, tidak.
How are you doing?
Apa kabarmu?
You were unconscious.
Anda tidak sadarkan diri.
I'm perfectly fine.
Saya baik-baik saja.
Come here.
Kemarilah.
I'm hurting.
Aku kesakitan.
Anywhere else?
Ada tempat lain?
I'm fine.
Saya baik-baik saja.
Don't ever jump in like that again.
Jangan pernah melompat seperti itu lagi.
I need to you stay in one piece so you can have my back.
Aku butuh kamu tetap sehat agar kamu bisa mendukungku.
You were lucky this time.
Kamu beruntung kali ini.
Imagine if your life was in danger…
Bayangkan jika hidup Anda dalam bahaya…
You think it would end with just a few eggs?
Menurutmu, ini hanya akan berakhir dengan beberapa telur saja?
Then stop putting me in that position.
Kalau begitu, berhentilah menempatkan saya dalam posisi itu.
I can't promise you that.
Aku tidak bisa menjanjikan itu padamu.
Then I can't either.
Kalau begitu, aku juga tidak bisa.
You make it seem like you're madly in love with me.
Kau membuat seolah-olah kau sangat mencintaiku.
This is what should be making the headlines.
Inilah yang seharusnya menjadi berita utama.
Babe, you sure this is right?
Sayang, kamu yakin ini benar?
Yeah, you're almost there.
Ya, kamu hampir sampai.
Okay.
Oke.
Now put one hand on your chest. Namaste.
Sekarang letakkan satu tangan di dada Anda. Namaste.
What? Nama-what-now?
Apa? Nama-apa-sekarang?
Namaste.
Namaste.
Right. Nama…
Baik. Nama…
FATHER
AYAH
-Babe, Father's calling. -What?
-Sayang, Ayah memanggil. -Apa?
Now? Why?
Sekarang? Mengapa?
-Does he know you're not at work? -Darn it.
-Apakah dia tahu kamu sedang tidak bekerja? -Sialan.
It's not even 8:00 yet.
Bahkan belum jam 8:00.
That's true. Did you do something wrong?
Benar sekali. Apakah kamu melakukan kesalahan?
No, I didn't.
Tidak, saya tidak melakukannya.
Hello, Father.
Halo, Ayah.
What? Seong Huiju did?
Apa? Seong Huiju yang melakukannya?
What in the… Babe, turn the TV on.
Astaga… Sayang, nyalakan TV-nya.
Yes.
Ya.
Last night, a traffic accident occurred on an outlying road in Gyeonggi Province.
Semalam, sebuah kecelakaan lalu lintas terjadi di jalan pinggiran Provinsi Gyeonggi.
-A speeding sports car -Yes, just a moment.
-Sebuah mobil sport yang melaju kencang -Ya, sebentar saja.
collided with a vehicle in the adjacent lane.
bertabrakan dengan kendaraan di jalur sebelahnya.
The driver of the sports car was identified as CEO Seong Huiju
Pengemudi mobil sport tersebut diidentifikasi sebagai CEO Seong Huiju.
of Castle Beauty, sparking further controversy.
dari Castle Beauty, yang memicu kontroversi lebih lanjut.
It is being reported that Ms. Seong's vehicle
Dilaporkan bahwa kendaraan milik Ibu Seong
was traveling 50 km/h over the speed limit…
sedang melaju 50 km/jam di atas batas kecepatan…
-What do we do? -Father, we'll come to you now.
-Apa yang harus kita lakukan? -Ayah, kami akan datang kepadamu sekarang.
-The police are still investigating… -All right.
-Polisi masih melakukan penyelidikan… -Baiklah.
You can't come in here.
Kamu tidak boleh masuk ke sini.
Seriously? Don't you remember me from last time?
Serius? Apa kau tidak ingat aku dari pertemuan sebelumnya?
I'm her assistant at Castle Beauty.
Saya asistennya di Castle Beauty.
You can't. Please step back.
Anda tidak bisa. Silakan mundur.
This is driving me insane.
Ini membuatku gila.
Then what about him?
Lalu bagaimana dengan dia?
Come on! Why do you only ever stop me?
Ayolah! Kenapa kau selalu menghentikanku?
Ms. Seong!
Nona Seong!
Ms. Do, come here.
Nona Do, kemarilah.
She's with me.
Dia bersamaku.
Those jerks are the worst.
Orang-orang brengsek itu memang yang terburuk.
Unbelievable.
Sulit dipercaya.
Why do they keep…
Mengapa mereka terus…
I told you I'm fine.
Aku sudah bilang aku baik-baik saja.
Nothing to worry about.
Tidak perlu khawatir.
I'm totally fine.
Aku baik-baik saja.
You'll fix this, right?
Kamu akan memperbaikinya, kan?
LIVE 3-MIN CHART
BAGAN LANGSUNG 3 MENIT
This was all part of the plan, right?
Ini semua bagian dari rencana, kan?
The chairman is freaking out. He wants you as soon as you're discharged.
Ketuanya panik sekali. Dia menginginkanmu segera setelah kamu keluar dari rumah sakit.
He knows I was injured?
Dia tahu aku cedera?
Of course…
Tentu saja…
he does.
Dia memang melakukannya.
And still, not a single word?
Dan tetap saja, tidak sepatah kata pun?
Not from Father, or even Seong Taeju?
Bukan dari Ayah, atau bahkan Seong Taeju?
I mean, how did you even end up in that accident?
Maksudku, bagaimana kamu bisa sampai terlibat dalam kecelakaan itu?
-Did you drink and drive? -No, I didn't.
-Apakah kamu minum sambil mengemudi? -Tidak, saya tidak.
I swear I didn't.
Aku bersumpah aku tidak melakukannya.
Then were you just speeding for the thrill of it?
Lalu, apakah Anda ngebut hanya untuk mencari sensasi?
You think I'm some kind of lunatic?
Kau pikir aku ini orang gila?
Just randomly speeding for the thrill of it?
Hanya ngebut sembarangan demi sensasi?
The car just took off.
Mobil itu langsung melaju pergi.
The brakes and all weren't working.
Rem dan semua sistem lainnya tidak berfungsi.
What in the world…
Astaga…
Then I'll first prepare a press release with the dashcam footage.
Kemudian, pertama-tama saya akan menyiapkan siaran pers beserta rekaman dashcam.
-You can't. -Why not?
-Kamu tidak bisa. -Mengapa tidak?
You just can't.
Kamu tidak bisa.
His Majesty was with me.
Yang Mulia Raja menyertai saya.
His Majesty?
Yang Mulia?
As in His Majesty the King?
Seperti Yang Mulia Raja?
The investigation won't be public.
Investigasi ini tidak akan dipublikasikan.
Damn it.
Brengsek.
It just never ends!
Ini tidak pernah berakhir!
Let's reconsider this.
Mari kita pertimbangkan kembali hal ini.
-Reconsider what? -This marriage.
-Mempertimbangkan kembali apa? -Pernikahan ini.
Can't you just call it off?
Tidak bisakah kamu membatalkannya saja?
You're seriously bringing that up now?
Kamu serius membahas itu sekarang?
There has been nothing but trouble since Prince I-AN entered your life.
Sejak Pangeran I-AN memasuki hidupmu, hanya ada masalah yang terjadi .
Egged at your own door over a little scandal.
Dilempari telur di depan pintu rumah sendiri karena skandal kecil.
One wrong turn in the palace made you an arsonist.
Satu kesalahan belok di istana bisa membuatmu menjadi pelaku pembakaran.
And this time, you nearly died.
Dan kali ini, kamu hampir mati.
Grand Prince I-AN was the one who saved me.
Pangeran Agung I-AN adalah orang yang menyelamatkan saya.
Wait, he was the one who saved you?
Tunggu, jadi dialah yang menyelamatkanmu?
Why are you two so caught up in this?
Mengapa kalian berdua begitu terobsesi dengan ini?
What do you mean?
Apa maksudmu?
I mean, why are you two overdoing it?
Maksudku, kenapa kalian berdua berlebihan?
You'll be divorced in three years anyway.
Lagipula kamu akan bercerai dalam tiga tahun lagi.
"Divorced"?
"Cerai"?
Jeongwoo.
Jeongwoo.
Where did you pop out from?
Kamu muncul dari mana?
Is your job fun?
Apakah pekerjaanmu menyenangkan?
Pardon?
Maaf?
Working at the palace.
Bekerja di istana.
Oh, the palace?
Oh, istana itu?
Well…
Dengan baik…
Why? Are you looking to work there too?
Mengapa? Apakah Anda juga ingin bekerja di sana?
Wow.
Wow.
When Ms. Seong moves into the palace…
Ketika Nona Seong pindah ke istana…
I'll be following her.
Aku akan mengikutinya.
So charismatic.
Sangat karismatik.
You said it was genuine.
Anda bilang itu asli.
Was it all a lie?
Apakah semuanya bohong?
I wouldn't go so far as to call it a lie…
Saya tidak akan menyebutnya sebagai kebohongan…
Seong Huiju.
Seong Huiju.
It's like a marriage of convenience.
Ini seperti pernikahan yang didasarkan pada kepentingan.
A simple exchange of services.
Pertukaran jasa yang sederhana.
You know plenty of people like that.
Kamu pasti kenal banyak orang seperti itu.
Don't make a big deal out of it.
Jangan terlalu memperbesar masalah ini.
That's completely different.
Itu sangat berbeda.
How so?
Bagaimana bisa?
Don't you know how dangerous the palace can be?
Apakah kamu tidak tahu betapa berbahayanya istana itu?
-Even this accident-- -I'm fine.
-Bahkan kecelakaan ini-- -Aku baik-baik saja.
You think I proposed without knowing that?
Kamu pikir aku melamar tanpa menyadari itu?
You proposed to him?
Kamu melamarnya?
Yeah. I was rejected about three times.
Ya. Saya ditolak sekitar tiga kali.
Listen.
Mendengarkan.
I have everything but status.
Aku punya segalanya kecuali status.
I have the money, talent, and ambition,
Saya punya uang, bakat, dan ambisi,
but status is the one thing I don't have.
tetapi status adalah satu hal yang tidak saya miliki.
If I just had that…
Seandainya aku memiliki itu…
I mean, why can't I have that too?
Maksudku, kenapa aku tidak bisa mendapatkan itu juga?
Is that all?
Hanya itu saja?
The reason you want to marry him.
Alasan mengapa kamu ingin menikah dengannya.
Is status all there is to it?
Apakah status adalah satu-satunya hal yang penting?
What else could there be?
Apa lagi yang mungkin ada?
Then do it with me.
Kalau begitu, lakukanlah bersamaku.
Do what?
Melakukan apa?
Just marry me instead.
Nikahi aku saja.
That will not do.
Itu tidak akan berhasil.
The Grand Prince, who had surgery, is returning to the palace.
Pangeran Agung, yang baru saja menjalani operasi, akan kembali ke istana.
Then surely, the King should as well.
Maka tentu saja, Raja pun seharusnya demikian.
But, Your Majesty…
Namun, Yang Mulia…
If the king remains out of sight,
Jika raja tetap tidak terlihat,
the people will come to think they do not need one.
Orang-orang akan berpikir bahwa mereka tidak membutuhkannya.
Do you not agree?
Apakah Anda tidak setuju?
I agree.
Saya setuju.
Your Royal Highness, I've been discharged…
Yang Mulia, saya telah dipulangkan…
Huh?
Hah?
Has he already been discharged?
Apakah dia sudah dipulangkan?
Your Royal Highness, Prime Minister Min has arrived.
Yang Mulia, Perdana Menteri Min telah tiba.
Show him in.
Persilakan dia masuk.
Your Royal Highness.
Yang Mulia.
You are all dismissed.
Kalian semua dipersilakan bubar.
I mean,
Maksud saya,
he should at least tell me if he's been discharged.
Setidaknya dia harus memberitahuku apakah dia sudah keluar dari rumah sakit.
Not a great sign for married life.
Bukan pertanda baik untuk kehidupan pernikahan.
He didn't say anything at the hospital?
Dia tidak mengatakan apa pun di rumah sakit?
When?
Kapan?
The last time I saw him was early this morning.
Terakhir kali saya melihatnya adalah pagi-pagi sekali.
What?
Apa?
But he was standing outside your room earlier.
Tapi tadi dia berdiri di luar kamarmu.
My room? When?
Kamarku? Kapan?
When Prime Minister Min stopped by.
Ketika Perdana Menteri Min mampir.
Then do it with me.
Kalau begitu, lakukanlah bersamaku.
Just marry me instead.
Nikahi aku saja.
Huh?
Hah?
So what you're saying is
Jadi yang Anda maksud adalah
Ms. Seong was kicked out by His Royal Highness?
Nona Seong diusir oleh Yang Mulia Pangeran?
Well, I mean, it was more like…
Maksudku, lebih tepatnya...
He asked that you return home.
Dia meminta agar kamu pulang.
That's the same thing!
Itu sama saja!
PRINCE
PANGERAN
Is he kidding me right now?
Apakah dia sedang bercanda denganku sekarang?
Your Ladyship! Wait, Your Ladyship.
Yang Mulia! Tunggu, Yang Mulia.
It's fine.
Tidak apa-apa.
The master of the house has already spoken.
Tuan rumah sudah berbicara.
It's not that.
Bukan itu masalahnya.
The hopae.
Hopae.
He would like it returned.
Dia ingin barang itu dikembalikan.
JUNIOR ALUM
ALUMNI JUNIOR
Is that all?
Hanya itu saja?
The reason you want to marry him.
Alasan mengapa kamu ingin menikah dengannya.
Is status all there is to it?
Apakah status adalah satu-satunya hal yang penting?
What else could there be?
Apa lagi yang mungkin ada?
Then do it with me.
Kalau begitu, lakukanlah bersamaku.
Just marry me instead.
Nikahi aku saja.
Say it to my face.
Katakan itu langsung di depanku.
Whatever it is.
Apapun itu.
It is a relief that I will never have to teach you.
Saya merasa lega karena saya tidak akan pernah harus mengajari Anda.
No matter how great a teacher may be,
Sehebat apa pun seorang guru,
there are things that simply cannot be taught.
Ada hal-hal yang memang tidak bisa diajarkan.
Pardon?
Maaf?
Your Royal Highness, Ms. Seong Huiju has arrived.
Yang Mulia, Nona Seong Huiju telah tiba.
Are you cleared to be out already?
Apakah kamu sudah diizinkan keluar?
That's your concern?
Itu yang menjadi kekhawatiranmu?
Why did you kick me out?
Mengapa kau mengusirku?
Because of the Queen Mother?
Karena Ibu Suri?
Or…
Atau…
because of Jeongwoo?
Karena Jeongwoo?
What about him?
Bagaimana dengan dia?
Didn't you overhear something?
Bukankah kamu mendengar sesuatu?
What?
Apa?
Never mind.
Sudahlah.
Then why did you kick me out?
Lalu mengapa kau mengusirku?
I need to know what's going on before I play along or not.
Saya perlu tahu apa yang sedang terjadi sebelum saya ikut bermain atau tidak.
Someone messed with your car.
Seseorang mengutak-atik mobilmu.
That is what caused the accident.
Itulah yang menyebabkan kecelakaan tersebut.
Who?
Siapa?
It's being investigated.
Hal itu sedang diselidiki.
We will catch them.
Kita akan menangkap mereka.
And so,
Jadi,
I'm changing the plan.
Saya mengubah rencana.
Let's…
Mari kita…
call off this marriage.
Batalkan pernikahan ini.
What… What was that?
Apa… Apa itu tadi?
Call what off now?
Batalkan apa sekarang?
The marriage.
Pernikahan.
But why?
Tapi kenapa?
Did Queen Mother tell you to do that?
Apakah Ibu Suri menyuruhmu melakukan itu?
Because of the accident?
Karena kecelakaan itu?
That was because His Majesty was relentless.
Itu karena Yang Mulia Raja pantang menyerah.
And you said someone messed with my car.
Dan kamu bilang ada yang mengutak-atik mobilku.
That makes me a victim too.
Itu membuatku menjadi korban juga.
Exactly.
Tepat.
That's why we must call it off.
Itulah mengapa kita harus membatalkannya.
If I married someone like you
Seandainya aku menikah dengan seseorang sepertimu
who breaks every rule and has enemies at every turn…
yang melanggar setiap aturan dan memiliki musuh di setiap kesempatan…
the Crown is bound to fall.
Mahkota itu pasti akan jatuh.
Father, this is a serious accident.
Ayah, ini kecelakaan serius.
See here.
Lihat di sini.
God, she's even driving on the other side of the road.
Ya Tuhan, dia bahkan mengemudi di sisi jalan yang berbeda.
If you ask me, at best, she's drunk.
Menurutku, paling banter dia sedang mabuk.
At worst, it's hard drugs. Nowadays, there's this…
Paling buruk, itu adalah narkoba keras. Sekarang ini, ada ini…
Right.
Benar.
I mean, she's always been desperate for attention.
Maksudku, dia selalu sangat haus perhatian.
Now that she's dating Prince I-AN, she's become a total hot tomato.
Sekarang setelah dia berpacaran dengan Pangeran I-AN, dia menjadi seperti tomat yang sangat menarik.
-And… -Potato.
-Dan… -Kentang.
It's "hot potato." Like a freshly baked hot potato.
Ini seperti "kentang panas." Seperti kentang panas yang baru saja dipanggang.
Oh, right. Potato.
Oh, benar. Kentang.
So, now…
Jadi, sekarang…
Babe, does that matter?
Sayang, apakah itu penting?
Tomato. Potato. Same difference.
Tomat. Kentang. Sama saja.
Sometimes, you can be…
Terkadang, Anda bisa menjadi…
Anyway, Father, this is totally a huge, glaring owner-related risk.
Pokoknya, Ayah, ini benar-benar risiko besar yang terkait dengan pemilik.
You saw how the stock had shot up over the last few days
Anda lihat bagaimana harga saham melonjak dalam beberapa hari terakhir.
and just took a nosedive, didn't you?
dan langsung anjlok, kan?
At this rate, Castle Beauty will just…
Dengan laju seperti ini, Castle Beauty akan...
So what?
Lalu kenapa?
You want to take over Beauty?
Anda ingin mengambil alih dunia kecantikan?
Is that any way to speak to your brother?
Apakah itu cara yang pantas untuk berbicara kepada saudaramu?
What is it?
Apa itu?
Let's make this quick. I'm busy.
Mari kita selesaikan ini dengan cepat. Saya sedang sibuk.
Explain yourself.
Jelaskan dirimu.
What is there to explain?
Apa yang perlu dijelaskan?
It's just as you see.
Seperti yang Anda lihat.
Can you handle the consequences?
Bisakah kamu menanggung konsekuensinya?
We'll issue a press release soon.
Kami akan segera mengeluarkan siaran pers.
Neither alcohol
Baik alkohol maupun alkohol
nor drugs were involved.
Tidak ada narkoba yang terlibat.
I heard they moved all your things
Aku dengar mereka memindahkan semua barangmu
out of his house today.
Dia keluar dari rumahnya hari ini.
Did you have me followed?
Apakah Anda menyuruh orang untuk mengikuti saya?
Explain yourself first!
Jelaskan dirimu terlebih dahulu!
It's just a lovers' spat.
Ini hanya pertengkaran kecil antara sepasang kekasih.
Satisfied?
Puas?
You call yourself a businesswoman,
Anda menyebut diri Anda seorang pengusaha wanita,
yet you don't even realize you're being used.
Namun, kau bahkan tidak menyadari bahwa kau sedang dimanfaatkan.
The Grand Prince has used you for all you're worth.
Pangeran Agung telah memanfaatkanmu sepenuhnya.
He acted like he was above status, as if he had no ambition for the throne.
Dia bersikap seolah-olah dirinya berada di atas status sosial, seolah-olah dia tidak memiliki ambisi untuk merebut takhta.
Now that he has everything…
Sekarang dia sudah memiliki segalanya…
he's tossing you out.
Dia mengusirmu.
So what?
Lalu kenapa?
What's the issue?
Apa masalahnya?
Two can play that game.
Dua orang bisa memainkan permainan itu.
Do you know how much our stock has jumped at the news
Tahukah Anda seberapa besar kenaikan harga saham kita setelah berita tersebut?
of Castle Group's Seong Huiju marrying into the royal family?
Apakah Seong Huiju dari Castle Group akan menikah dengan keluarga kerajaan?
Hey, kid. It all tanked today.
Hei, Nak. Semuanya berantakan hari ini.
It will bounce right back after the press release, damn it.
Harganya akan langsung naik kembali setelah siaran pers, sialan!
They're even asking if the "Castle" name was part of some grand plan.
Mereka bahkan mempertanyakan apakah nama "Castle" merupakan bagian dari rencana besar.
Haven't you seen the news?
Apakah kamu belum melihat berita?
Did it ever cross your mind that it'll put a bigger target on our backs?
Apakah pernah terlintas di benakmu bahwa ini akan membuat kita menjadi sasaran yang lebih besar?
So we take a few hits!
Jadi, kita akan menerima beberapa pukulan!
A few hits won't kill you.
Beberapa kali terkena tembakan tidak akan membunuhmu.
And even if it did, what of it?
Dan bahkan jika itu terjadi, lalu apa gunanya?
We all end up dead anyway.
Pada akhirnya kita semua akan mati juga.
What, do you plan to live forever?
Apa, kamu berencana hidup selamanya?
Next time, just text me instead.
Lain kali, kirim pesan saja.
If you want to yell that badly, then feel free to call.
Jika kamu sangat ingin berteriak, silakan telepon saja.
-Sit down. -I have plans.
-Silakan duduk. -Aku ada rencana.
Seong Huiju!
Seong Huiju!
It's me.
Ini aku.
I need you to look into something for me.
Aku butuh bantuanmu untuk menyelidiki sesuatu.
Find out who last worked on my car.
Cari tahu siapa yang terakhir kali mengerjakan mobil saya.
Dig up everything you possibly can on them.
Gali semua informasi yang mungkin Anda temukan tentang mereka.
A grand prince of this nation can't…
Seorang pangeran agung bangsa ini tidak bisa…
break an engagement.
Membatalkan pertunangan.
Technically, there's nothing to break. We were never engaged.
Secara teknis, tidak ada yang bisa dirusak. Kami tidak pernah bertunangan.
Are you kidding?
Kamu bercanda?
After all that talk about getting married and living together?
Setelah semua pembicaraan tentang menikah dan hidup bersama?
We never lived together.
Kami tidak pernah tinggal bersama.
-I was at the palace, and she was-- -Listen.
-Aku berada di istana, dan dia-- -Dengarkan.
Even if you killed someone, I would take your side.
Sekalipun kau membunuh seseorang, aku akan tetap membela dirimu.
But this is not cool. It's--
Tapi ini tidak keren. Ini--
Why would you side with a murderer?
Mengapa Anda membela seorang pembunuh?
You must've had your reasons.
Anda pasti punya alasan sendiri.
So, why did you break it off?
Jadi, mengapa kalian memutuskan hubungan?
-I didn't "break"-- -Seriously? Come on.
-Aku tidak "patah"-- -Serius? Ayolah.
That's not what I'm asking.
Bukan itu yang saya tanyakan.
Why did you break it off?
Mengapa kamu memutuskan hubungan?
To keep her alive.
Untuk menjaga agar dia tetap hidup.
Mother, should we pick up fried chicken on the way to the palace?
Ibu, apakah sebaiknya kita membeli ayam goreng dalam perjalanan ke istana?
Fried chicken?
Ayam goreng?
Hwan texted and said he wanted some.
Hwan mengirim pesan dan mengatakan dia menginginkan beberapa.
He's always making me do stuff like this.
Dia selalu menyuruhku melakukan hal-hal seperti ini.
Shall we, then?
Kalau begitu, mari kita mulai?
Yes, Mother.
Ya, Ibu.
Mother!
Ibu!
Mother, should we pick up fried chicken on the way to the palace?
Ibu, apakah sebaiknya kita membeli ayam goreng dalam perjalanan ke istana?
Shall we, then?
Kalau begitu, mari kita mulai?
Mother…
Ibu…
There wasn't a doubt in my mind.
Tidak ada keraguan sedikit pun dalam pikiran saya.
It was a moment I'd regretted countless times.
Itu adalah momen yang telah saya sesali berkali-kali.
That's what changed my mind.
Itulah yang mengubah pikiranku.
It was just an accident.
Itu hanya kecelakaan.
It wasn't even your fault, so why?
Ini bahkan bukan salahmu, jadi kenapa?
It was my fault.
Itu salahku.
Signs of deliberate tampering
Tanda-tanda perusakan yang disengaja
were found in the accident vehicle.
ditemukan di dalam kendaraan yang mengalami kecelakaan.
We'll need to investigate further to determine if they were targeting
Kita perlu menyelidiki lebih lanjut untuk menentukan apakah mereka menargetkan
His Majesty or Ms. Seong.
Yang Mulia atau Nona Seong.
However, do not concern yourself too much.
Namun, jangan terlalu khawatir.
I will do everything in my power to protect
Saya akan melakukan segala yang saya mampu untuk melindungi
His Majesty, Your Royal Highness,
Yang Mulia, Baginda Raja/Ratu,
and the Crown.
dan Mahkota.
In turn,
Pada gilirannya,
I'd like to ask you
Saya ingin bertanya kepada Anda
to protect Ms. Seong Huiju.
untuk melindungi Ibu Seong Huiju.
Please cast her far away from the palace.
Tolong usir dia jauh dari istana.
I sincerely implore you, Your Royal Highness.
Saya dengan tulus memohon kepada Anda, Yang Mulia.
That is why
Itulah sebabnya
I must step aside.
Saya harus minggir dulu.
Your Royal Highness.
Yang Mulia.
Thus,
Dengan demikian,
I want to do something.
Aku ingin melakukan sesuatu.
Pardon?
Maaf?
A parting gift.
Hadiah perpisahan.
For her.
Untuknya.
The Inner Court Banquet guest list,
Daftar tamu Perjamuan Halaman Dalam,
proposed by the Royal Secretariat.
diusulkan oleh Sekretariat Kerajaan.
PALACE EVENT HOSTED FOR LADIES OF THE INNER COURT
ACARA ISTANA DISELENGGARAKAN UNTUK PARA WANITA ANGGOTA ISTANA DALAM
TRADITIONALLY HELD SINCE THE JOSEON DYNASTY
TRADISIONALNYA DIADAKAN SEJAK DINASTI JOSEON
Remove the scandal-ridden figures.
Singkirkan tokoh-tokoh yang terlibat skandal.
No new money either.
Tidak ada uang baru juga.
The merits of these two are comparable.
Keunggulan keduanya sebanding.
Bring me the details of their families.
Berikan saya detail tentang keluarga mereka.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Baik, Yang Mulia.
Your standards rise every year.
Standar Anda meningkat setiap tahun.
The more exclusive the guest list,
Semakin eksklusif daftar tamunya,
the deeper the despair of the uninvited.
semakin dalam keputusasaan orang-orang yang tidak diundang.
And with it comes the greater delight of those invited.
Dan bersamaan dengan itu hadir pula kegembiraan yang lebih besar bagi mereka yang diundang.
INNER COURT BANQUET GUEST LIST
DAFTAR TAMU JAMUAN PERJAMUAN DI LAPANGAN DALAM
Another gathering of the usual suspects this year.
Pertemuan lain dari orang-orang yang sudah biasa ditemui tahun ini.
All nobility.
Semua kaum bangsawan.
The competition is fiercer every year.
Persaingan semakin ketat setiap tahunnya.
It does offer many benefits.
Hal ini memang menawarkan banyak manfaat.
That is true.
Itu benar.
But if they managed to secure an invite,
Namun jika mereka berhasil mendapatkan undangan,
they must already possess plenty of money and land.
Mereka pasti sudah memiliki banyak uang dan tanah.
That's precisely why they're willing to die for royal prestige.
Justru karena itulah mereka rela mati demi kehormatan kerajaan.
It's the only thing their money can't buy.
Itulah satu-satunya hal yang tidak bisa dibeli dengan uang mereka.
Ma'am.
Bu.
I had to jump through some pretty high hoops to secure
Saya harus melewati beberapa rintangan yang cukup tinggi untuk mendapatkannya.
this Inner Court Banquet guest list.
Daftar tamu untuk Jamuan Makan Malam di Halaman Dalam ini.
A lot of familiar faces, right?
Banyak wajah yang familiar, kan?
A gathering of female business leaders in their thirties…
Pertemuan para pemimpin bisnis wanita berusia tiga puluhan…
Still just 20 of them, right?
Masih ada 20 orang, kan?
Not even enough for a soccer match.
Bahkan tidak cukup untuk satu pertandingan sepak bola.
But, ma'am, you said so yourself.
Tapi, Bu, Anda sendiri yang mengatakannya.
"One absolute is worth more than a hundred maybes."
"Satu kepastian lebih berharga daripada seratus kemungkinan."
These are 20 absolutes.
Ini adalah 20 hal mutlak.
All backed by the Crown, no less!
Semua itu didukung oleh Kerajaan, tidak kurang!
You once called this the most luxurious marketing strategy…
Anda pernah menyebut ini sebagai strategi pemasaran paling mewah…
So what's your point?
Jadi apa intinya?
Moving on.
Mari kita lanjutkan.
Since you have ties with the palace and all, we thought
Karena Anda punya hubungan dengan istana dan sebagainya, kami pikir...
one of the guests could be a new face of our luxury line.
Salah satu tamu bisa jadi wajah baru dari lini produk mewah kami.
Yes, so we…
Ya, jadi kami…
Just a moment. Oh.
Tunggu sebentar. Oh.
Hello.
Halo.
MS. SEONG HUIJU, YOU ARE CORDIALLY INVITED TO THE INNER COURT BANQUET
Nona Seong Huiju, Anda diundang dengan hormat ke Jamuan Makan di Halaman Dalam.
Me?
Aku?
Yes, Ms. Seong.
Ya, Nona Seong.
The Inner Court Banquet is a very important annual event.
Jamuan Makan Malam di Halaman Dalam adalah acara tahunan yang sangat penting.
Of course, I'm aware of the Inner Court Banquet.
Tentu saja, saya mengetahui tentang Jamuan Makan Malam di Istana Dalam.
But I thought only noblewomen were invited to this.
Tapi kukira hanya wanita bangsawan yang diundang ke acara ini.
What? No such criterion exists…
Apa? Kriteria seperti itu tidak ada…
It certainly doesn't,
Tentu saja tidak,
but that's how it's been done.
Tapi memang begitulah cara yang selama ini dilakukan.
For 600 years, without a single exception.
Selama 600 tahun, tanpa satu pun pengecualian.
The thing about change is that it happens gradually…
Yang perlu diingat tentang perubahan adalah bahwa perubahan itu terjadi secara bertahap…
So? How? Why?
Jadi? Bagaimana? Mengapa?
Why have I suddenly been invited?
Mengapa saya tiba-tiba diundang?
Yes, well, you've experienced some hardships recently,
Ya, memang, kamu telah mengalami beberapa kesulitan akhir-akhir ini,
and the press release about your breakup is about to go out.
dan siaran pers tentang perpisahan kalian akan segera dirilis.
So to make it clear the palace wasn't responsible for your breakup…
Jadi, untuk memperjelas, istana bukanlah penyebab putusnya hubungan kalian…
You want to stage a performance for the public?
Anda ingin menggelar pertunjukan untuk umum?
Yes, you see,
Ya, Anda lihat,
the dress codes for the two parts are different.
Aturan berpakaian untuk kedua bagian tersebut berbeda.
It's customary to wear a dangui for the reception.
Merupakan kebiasaan untuk mengenakan dangui untuk resepsi pernikahan.
The Queen Mother will wear white, so it's best to avoid that color.
Ibu Suri akan mengenakan pakaian berwarna putih, jadi sebaiknya hindari warna itu.
No thanks.
Tidak, terima kasih.
To what exactly? The dangui?
Tepatnya, apa? Dangui?
The Inner Court Banquet.
Jamuan Makan di Halaman Dalam.
Ms. Seong.
Ibu Seong.
Why?
Mengapa?
The Inner Court Banquet? You don't want to attend?
Jamuan Makan Malam Istana Dalam? Anda tidak ingin hadir?
Silly me, how did I forget to mention this?
Bodohnya aku, bagaimana bisa aku lupa menyebutkan ini?
Attending it once will lead to many more royal invitations.
Menghadirinya sekali akan berujung pada banyak undangan kerajaan lainnya.
Even royal patronage for your overseas business.
Bahkan dukungan kerajaan untuk bisnis luar negeri Anda.
Okay. Above all else,
Oke. Di atas segalanya,
this will confirm that you two didn't end things badly,
Ini akan memastikan bahwa kalian berdua tidak mengakhiri hubungan dengan buruk.
and that you remain on good terms with the Crown.
dan bahwa Anda tetap menjalin hubungan baik dengan Kerajaan.
We can pivot to an "it's all cool" narrative--
Kita bisa beralih ke narasi "semuanya baik-baik saja"--
-That would be excellent. -Mm-hmm.
-Itu akan sangat bagus. -Mm-hmm.
You've always wanted an invite.
Kamu selalu menginginkan undangan itu.
That was before marriage was on the table.
Itu terjadi sebelum pernikahan menjadi agenda utama.
No thanks.
Tidak, terima kasih.
But still, His Royal Highness personally…
Namun tetap saja, Yang Mulia secara pribadi…
No…
TIDAK…
thank…
terima kasih…
you.
Anda.
What?
Apa?
So? You just left?
Jadi? Kamu baru saja pergi?
What choice did I have? She was about to murder me in broad daylight.
Pilihan apa yang saya miliki? Dia hendak membunuh saya di siang bolong.
I heard you moved Seong Huiju out of your private residence.
Saya dengar Anda memindahkan Seong Huiju dari kediaman pribadi Anda.
What are you playing at?
Kamu sedang bermain apa?
I am protecting her.
Aku melindunginya.
Her ties to the Crown
Hubungannya dengan Kerajaan
have only led her to misfortune.
hanya membawanya pada kemalangan.
Then,
Kemudian,
ensure she no longer has any ties to the Crown.
memastikan dia tidak lagi memiliki hubungan apa pun dengan Kerajaan.
That is my intention.
Itulah niat saya.
I will not pursue
Saya tidak akan mengejar
marriage with Seong Huiju.
pernikahan dengan Seong Huiju.
In turn,
Pada gilirannya,
I ask that you invite her to the Inner Court Banquet.
I ask that you invite her to the Inner Court Banquet.
I do not wish to see her suffer
I do not wish to see her suffer
because of our parting.
because of our parting.
Summon her to the palace.
Summon her to the palace.
Ms. Seong Huiju?
Ms. Seong Huiju?
You want me to?
You want me to?
I shall persuade her myself.
I shall persuade her myself.
No thanks.
No thanks.
No, thank you.
No, thank you.
Who is he to summon me?
Who is he to summon me?
Is the fried chicken here?
Is the fried chicken here?
What? You ordered fried chicken again?
What? You ordered fried chicken again?
You open it.
You open it.
Mmm.
Mmm.
People have nothing on fried chicken, right?
People have nothing on fried chicken, right?
It shows up right on time when you call them.
It shows up right on time when you call them.
You never get sick of it.
You never get sick of it.
Always so reliable.
Always so reliable.
-Wait… -What?
-Wait… -What?
Are you upset you got dumped?
Are you upset you got dumped?
Why would you say that when I'm enjoying fried chicken?
Why would you say that when I'm enjoying fried chicken?
I'm done.
I'm done.
Oh, I mean…
Oh, I mean…
Why are you so upset?
Why are you so upset?
It was all pretend.
It was all pretend.
That's exactly why.
That's exactly why.
Relationships end when one side loses interest,
Relationships end when one side loses interest,
whether the other likes it or not.
whether the other likes it or not.
But that's not what this was.
But that's not what this was.
This was strictly a contract.
This was strictly a contract.
Father was right.
Father was right.
I'm a businesswoman. I should've known better than to trust a stranger.
I'm a businesswoman. I should've known better than to trust a stranger.
I should've drawn up a contract.
I should've drawn up a contract.
Ms. Seong, the invite--
Ms. Seong, the invite--
No thanks.
No thanks.
Ms. Seong.
Ms. Seong.
-You're really not going? -No, thank you!
-You're really not going? -No, thank you!
Is she dumb?
Is she dumb?
Just give up already.
Just give up already.
She doesn't want anything to do with you.
She doesn't want anything to do with you.
Choi Hyeon.
Choi Hyeon.
I mean, I can't blame her.
I mean, I can't blame her.
You dumped her and now you're acting so uncool.
You dumped her and now you're acting so uncool.
Hey, Ms. Seong.
Hey, Ms. Seong.
I went to the repair shop and secured
I went to the repair shop and secured
the résumé of the bastard who tampered with your car and fled.
the résumé of the bastard who tampered with your car and fled.
They ran a search with his photo,
They ran a search with his photo,
but he doesn't seem to have any priors.
but he doesn't seem to have any priors.
He must've bought something there at least once.
He must've bought something there at least once.
What?
What?
There's a convenience store in front of the shop.
There's a convenience store in front of the shop.
Oh, right.
Oh, right.
Scour their CCTV footage.
Scour their CCTV footage.
I want his purchase history.
I want his purchase history.
Say it to my face.
Say it to my face.
Whatever it is.
Whatever it is.
Are you afraid to go to the banquet?
Are you afraid to go to the banquet?
I will prepare everything you need.
I will prepare everything you need.
From the clothes
From the clothes
to the etiquette lessons.
to the etiquette lessons.
Why?
Why?
I break every rule and have enemies at every turn.
I break every rule and have enemies at every turn.
-So why would I go there? -Seong Huiju.
-So why would I go there? -Seong Huiju.
Then provide me with a convincing reason.
Then provide me with a convincing reason.
You risked your life to save me, just to break off the engagement.
You risked your life to save me, just to break off the engagement.
And now you're inviting me to the Inner Court Banquet?
And now you're inviting me to the Inner Court Banquet?
A split personality?
A split personality?
I am trying to protect you!
I am trying to protect you!
We're not even married…
We're not even married…
and you've been attacked multiple times.
and you've been attacked multiple times.
And once the breakup news breaks,
And once the breakup news breaks,
it'll only get worse.
it'll only get worse.
So what?
So what?
"Social ascent is dangerous. Be content with an invite to the banquet."
"Social ascent is dangerous. Be content with an invite to the banquet."
-Is that it? -Just stay out of harm's way.
-Is that it? -Just stay out of harm's way.
Is that so difficult?
Is that so difficult?
Coward.
Coward.
What?
What?
-What are you… -You like cats.
-What are you… -You like cats.
Try protecting them.
Try protecting them.
I'm going to attack them.
I'm going to attack them.
What the hell are you doing?
What the hell are you doing?
This is how you protect someone.
This is how you protect someone.
You go on the offensive.
Anda mengambil inisiatif menyerang.
You fight back.
Kamu melawan balik.
You never learned to bend.
Kamu tidak pernah belajar membungkuk.
You only know how to bend. That's why you lose to people beneath you.
Kamu hanya tahu cara membungkuk. Itulah sebabnya kamu kalah dari orang-orang yang lebih rendah darimu.
I asked you for status,
Saya menanyakan status Anda,
not a cozy cradle to hide from the world.
bukan buaian nyaman untuk bersembunyi dari dunia.
Do not bend to their will.
Jangan tunduk pada keinginan mereka.
Do not back away
Jangan mundur
and do not compromise.
dan jangan berkompromi.
That's how you and I both
Begitulah cara kita berdua
get what we want.
mendapatkan apa yang kita inginkan.
She is one scary lady.
Dia adalah wanita yang menakutkan.
I know all's fair in love and war,
Aku tahu segala cara diperbolehkan dalam cinta dan perang,
but isn't this taking it too far?
Tapi bukankah ini sudah keterlaluan?
Is a "safe exit" an option here?
Apakah "jalan keluar yang aman" merupakan pilihan di sini?
I told you I hurt myself.
Aku sudah bilang aku melukai diriku sendiri.
Even so, how could she let your precious body be injured?
Meskipun begitu, bagaimana mungkin dia membiarkan tubuhmu yang berharga terluka?
She has crossed the line.
Dia sudah melewati batas.
I told you she didn't.
Sudah kubilang dia tidak melakukannya.
She never released the arrow.
Dia tidak pernah melepaskan anak panah itu.
What?
Apa?
She never crossed the line.
Dia tidak pernah melewati batas.
My eyes are fried.
Mataku terasa perih sekali.
He must've been super diligent.
Dia pasti sangat rajin.
Never going to the convenience store across the street.
Tidak pernah pergi ke toko serba ada di seberang jalan.
My thoughts exactly.
Saya setuju sekali.
Wait.
Tunggu.
I think this is him.
Saya rasa ini dia.
Take a look at this.
Lihatlah ini.
-It's him, right? -Yeah, it is.
-Dia, kan? -Ya, benar.
Castle Pay!
Castle Pay!
-Yeah, he used Castle Pay! -He did.
-Ya, dia menggunakan Castle Pay! -Benar.
Good job!
Kerja bagus!
Hold on.
Tunggu.
But the CEO of Castle Card is Senior Managing Director Seong, isn't it?
Tapi CEO Castle Card adalah Senior Managing Director Seong, kan?
Let me get this straight.
Coba saya pastikan.
You need help from your dear brother.
Kamu membutuhkan bantuan dari saudaramu tersayang.
Yes.
Ya.
I mean, sure.
Maksudku, tentu saja.
I could do that for you, but--
Aku bisa melakukannya untukmu, tapi--
Who is he anyway?
Siapa dia sebenarnya?
He's trying to kill me.
Dia berusaha membunuhku.
This kid…
Anak ini…
Do you take me for a sucker?
Apakah kamu menganggapku bodoh?
Are you serious?
Kamu serius?
So show me what you can do.
Jadi, tunjukkan padaku apa yang bisa kamu lakukan.
I want some vigilante justice.
Aku menginginkan keadilan ala main hakim sendiri.
This kid…
Anak ini…
Who is this guy anyway?
Sebenarnya siapa pria ini?
Then do it with me.
Kalau begitu, lakukanlah bersamaku.
Just marry me instead.
Nikahi aku saja.
Why would I marry you?
Mengapa aku harus menikahimu?
Why not?
Mengapa tidak?
It's not like you have feelings
Bukan berarti kamu punya perasaan.
for either of us.
untuk kita berdua.
You have a five-year term.
Anda memiliki masa jabatan lima tahun.
It doesn't matter if I mess up or divorce him.
Tidak masalah jika aku membuat kesalahan atau menceraikannya.
He'll be a royal for life.
Dia akan menjadi bangsawan seumur hidup.
But you're different.
Tapi kamu berbeda.
You should serve another term.
Anda harus menjalani masa jabatan berikutnya.
Pull yourself together.
Tenangkan dirimu.
Is it weighing on your mind?
Apakah hal itu mengganggu pikiranmu?
I heard from Aide Choi.
Saya mendapat kabar dari Aide Choi.
That there was an argument at your private residence.
Terjadi pertengkaran di kediaman pribadi Anda.
Choi Hyeon…
Choi Hyeon…
He can be quite the chatterbox.
Dia bisa jadi sangat cerewet.
Just let her win if you can.
Biarkan saja dia menang jika memungkinkan.
She is already under the cutting scrutiny
Dia sudah berada di bawah pengawasan ketat.
of the court of public opinion.
dari pengadilan opini publik.
PRINCE
PANGERAN
Hello.
Halo.
The invitation has already been sent.
Undangan sudah dikirim.
So you cannot decline.
Jadi Anda tidak bisa menolak.
It's for your sake.
Ini demi kebaikanmu.
I know.
Aku tahu.
I'm sorry.
Saya minta maaf.
I never meant to hurt you.
Aku tidak pernah bermaksud menyakitimu.
Or the cat.
Atau kucing itu.
I know.
Aku tahu.
I'm sorry too.
Aku juga minta maaf.
For not keeping my promise.
Karena tidak menepati janji.
As long as you know.
Asalkan kamu tahu.
CASTLE BEAUTY
KEINDAHAN ISTANA
I heard you will be attending.
Saya dengar Anda akan hadir.
Yes, well, he just insisted it would be in my best interest.
Ya, dia bersikeras bahwa itu akan menjadi yang terbaik untuk saya.
There's one thing you should be aware of.
Ada satu hal yang perlu Anda ketahui.
-Just a moment. -Sure.
-Tunggu sebentar. -Tentu.
-Please continue. -All right.
-Silakan lanjutkan. -Baik.
All the other invited guests hold official rank.
Semua tamu undangan lainnya memegang pangkat resmi.
In the royal court, rank defines one's place in the hierarchy.
Di istana kerajaan, pangkat menentukan kedudukan seseorang dalam hierarki.
-Hierarchy? -Yes. Uh…
-Hierarki? -Ya. Eh…
I'm sure you noticed after attending a few royal events.
Saya yakin Anda menyadarinya setelah menghadiri beberapa acara kerajaan.
When you're with someone of a higher rank,
Saat Anda bersama seseorang yang berkedudukan lebih tinggi,
you must walk behind them. That's the custom.
Anda harus berjalan di belakang mereka. Itu sudah menjadi kebiasaan.
I'll keep that in mind.
Akan saya ingat itu.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
And there's this.
Dan ada ini.
Here.
Di Sini.
The first half is a smaller gathering where the Queen Mother
Bagian pertama adalah pertemuan yang lebih kecil di mana Ibu Suri hadir.
and the guests mingle.
dan para tamu berbaur.
The second half is a ball.
Babak kedua adalah sebuah bola.
They call it an "after-party,"
Mereka menyebutnya "pesta setelah acara,"
but with the guests' partners, Cabinet members, and royal family members
tetapi dengan pasangan para tamu, anggota Kabinet, dan anggota keluarga kerajaan.
all attending, it's larger in scale than the first part.
Dengan semua yang hadir, acara ini berskala lebih besar daripada bagian pertama.
I read an article about this while studying abroad.
Saya membaca sebuah artikel tentang ini saat belajar di luar negeri.
You wear gowns and dance…
Kamu mengenakan gaun dan menari…
That's correct.
Itu benar.
Then what will Ms. Seong's rank be?
Lalu, apa pangkat Ibu Seong nantinya?
Ms. Seong is super accomplished and all,
Ibu Seong sangat berprestasi dan sebagainya,
but she has no official rank.
tetapi dia tidak memiliki pangkat resmi.
-What? -Well…
-Apa? -Baiklah…
She's neither a public official
Dia bukan seorang pejabat publik.
nor a noble.
juga bukan seorang bangsawan.
So Ms. Seong will be sitting at the very back of the room
Jadi, Ibu Seong akan duduk di bagian paling belakang ruangan.
and will always be last in line.
dan akan selalu menjadi yang terakhir dalam antrean.
I would be in front of the line if I were married, right?
Kalau aku sudah menikah, aku pasti akan berada di barisan terdepan , kan?
"The attendees receive honorary decorations
Para hadirin menerima tanda kehormatan.
from the royal family and gain the privilege
dari keluarga kerajaan dan mendapatkan hak istimewa
of accompanying the court when it hosts diplomatic events,
mendampingi pengadilan ketika menyelenggarakan acara diplomatik,
starting with the year they are invited."
dimulai dari tahun mereka diundang."
It is a relief that I will never have to teach you.
Saya merasa lega karena saya tidak akan pernah harus mengajari Anda.
As if she'd ever grant me such privileges.
Seolah-olah dia akan pernah memberiku hak istimewa seperti itu.
PRINCE
PANGERAN
Hello?
Halo?
Right now?
Sekarang?
What's this about?
Ini tentang apa?
Why not?
Mengapa tidak?
This will be the last time.
Ini akan menjadi yang terakhir kalinya.
Where did you ever find the nerve to wear that cheollik?
Dari mana kau mendapatkan keberanian untuk mengenakan topi cheollik itu?
Was that just a stylistic choice?
Apakah itu hanya pilihan gaya?
I'm doing all this for your sake…
Aku melakukan semua ini demi dirimu…
What are you doing?
Apa yang sedang kamu lakukan?
Don't mind me. Just practicing.
Jangan hiraukan aku. Aku hanya sedang berlatih.
-Practicing what? -Walking according to rank.
-Berlatih apa? -Berjalan sesuai dengan peringkat.
I'll definitely end up walking ahead that day if I don't practice now.
Aku pasti akan berjalan lebih dulu hari itu jika aku tidak berlatih sekarang.
Because I'm always a trendsetter, leading the way.
Karena saya selalu menjadi pelopor tren, memimpin jalan.
-A word, please! -Please look over here!
-Sebentar, ya! -Silakan lihat ke sini!
-Over here! -Give us a pose!
-Ke sini! -Berposelah!
I trust all the preparations are in order?
Saya yakin semua persiapan sudah berjalan dengan baik?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Baik, Yang Mulia.
Bye.
Selamat tinggal.
Wait.
Tunggu.
"Leading the way."
"Memimpin jalan."
How do you do it?
Bagaimana Anda melakukannya?
I just never learned.
Aku memang tidak pernah belajar.
I was always the one following behind.
Aku selalu menjadi orang yang mengikuti di belakang.
You just need to walk by my side.
Kamu hanya perlu berjalan di sisiku.
I'll teach you.
Aku akan mengajarimu.
Now that Dano, when yang energy is said to be at its peak, has passed,
Sekarang Dano, ketika energi Yang dikatakan berada pada puncaknya, telah berlalu,
the Inner Court Banquet has finally commenced.
Jamuan Makan Malam di Halaman Dalam akhirnya dimulai.
It's a gathering of 20 young women
Ini adalah pertemuan 20 wanita muda.
centered around the Queen Mother, the head of the Inner Court.
berpusat di sekitar Ibu Suri, kepala Istana Dalam.
This year's guest list includes Seong Huiju, CEO of Castle Beauty,
Daftar tamu tahun ini termasuk Seong Huiju, CEO Castle Beauty,
drawing significant attention.
menarik perhatian yang signifikan.
-Babe! -You scared me.
-Sayang! -Kamu membuatku kaget.
Babe.
Bayi.
I found the punk who rigged her car.
Aku menemukan berandal yang memasang alat pengganggu di mobilnya.
You did?
Benarkah?
Yeah, but…
Ya, tapi…
But?
Tetapi?
He's dead.
Dia sudah meninggal.
-What? -He died.
-Apa? -Dia meninggal.
Yesterday.
Kemarin.
JUNIOR 4TH RANK, SENIOR 4TH RANK
PERINGKAT 4 JUNIOR, PERINGKAT 4 SENIOR
JUNIOR 5TH RANK
PERINGKAT KE-5 JUNIOR
JUNIOR 6TH RANK
PERINGKAT KELAS 6 JUNIOR
SEONG HUIJU, COMMONER
SEONG HUIJU, ORANG BIASA
For all her much-touted success abroad,
Terlepas dari semua kesuksesannya yang banyak dipuji di luar negeri,
she was never invited.
Dia tidak pernah diundang.
It seems being the Grand Prince's woman
Sepertinya menjadi wanita Pangeran Agung
outweighs any barrier of status.
lebih penting daripada hambatan status apa pun.
If she successfully marries him, she will be royalty,
Jika dia berhasil menikah dengannya, dia akan menjadi seorang bangsawan.
so they must be keeping up appearances.
jadi mereka pasti sedang menjaga penampilan.
Even so,
Meskipun demikian,
is she not someone who caused a public scandal?
Bukankah dia seseorang yang menyebabkan skandal publik?
If she had been a guest last year,
Seandainya dia menjadi tamu tahun lalu,
at least they could have used her achievements as an excuse.
Setidaknya mereka bisa menggunakan prestasinya sebagai alasan.
The royal family is such a joke these days.
Keluarga kerajaan sekarang ini benar-benar menjadi bahan lelucon.
-Your Majesty.
-Yang Mulia.
SEONG HUIJU, COMMONER
SEONG HUIJU, ORANG BIASA
Were you speaking ill of someone who is not even here?
Apakah kamu menjelek-jelekkan seseorang yang bahkan tidak ada di sini?
Pardon?
Maaf?
I should have come later.
Seharusnya aku datang lebih siang.
Considering you saw fit
Mengingat Anda merasa pantas
to drag the royal family into your gossip.
untuk menyeret keluarga kerajaan ke dalam gosip Anda.
Ms. Seong, over here!
Nona Seong, kemari!
-Ms. Seong, over here! -Please look here!
-Nona Seong, kemari! -Silakan lihat ke sini!
Your Majesty.
Yang Mulia.
I am Huiju of the Seong Family.
Saya Huiju dari Keluarga Seong.
-Ms. Seong. -Ms. Seong!
-Nona Seong. -Nona Seong!
How does it feel to be back at the palace since going public?
Bagaimana rasanya kembali ke istana setelah hubungan kalian terungkap ke publik?
What was the palace's stance on the accident?
Bagaimana sikap istana terhadap kecelakaan itu?
Is there a reason why you arrived after Her Majesty?
Apakah ada alasan mengapa Anda tiba setelah Yang Mulia?
-Please give us a comment! -Please!
-Silakan beri kami komentar! -Tolong!
-We await your response. -Give us a comment.
-Kami menunggu tanggapan Anda. -Berikan komentar Anda.
Unfortunately, I still do not know my way around the palace.
Sayangnya, saya masih belum hafal seluk-beluk istana ini.
I ended up losing my way for a moment.
Aku akhirnya tersesat sejenak.
Please forgive me,
Mohon maafkan saya,
Your Majesty.
Yang Mulia.
I was told the Royal Secretariat provided you with guidance.
Saya diberitahu bahwa Sekretariat Kerajaan telah memberikan panduan kepada Anda.
Did you avoid wearing a dangui for some particular reason?
Apakah Anda menghindari mengenakan dangui karena alasan tertentu?
Ah!
Ah!
I was led to believe that custom was not mandatory.
Saya diberi tahu bahwa adat istiadat tidak wajib.
Is it not to your liking?
Apakah ini tidak sesuai dengan selera Anda?
How could it not be?
Bagaimana mungkin tidak?
-Would you care to respond? -Ms. Seong, over here.
-Apakah Anda bersedia menjawab? -Nona Seong, di sini.
The snacks Your Majesty sent for Children's Day
Camilan yang Yang Mulia kirimkan untuk Hari Anak
brought great joy to all the patients in the pediatric ward.
membawa kegembiraan besar bagi semua pasien di bangsal anak.
I am more than happy to help in any way I can.
Saya akan sangat senang membantu dengan cara apa pun yang saya bisa.
Do not hesitate to let me know.
Jangan ragu untuk memberi tahu saya.
I heard Your Majesty enjoyed my performances.
Saya dengar Yang Mulia menikmati penampilan saya.
If Your Majesty could attend the next one, I would be greatly honored…
Jika Yang Mulia berkenan hadir pada acara berikutnya, saya akan merasa sangat terhormat…
Perhaps the summer is to thank,
Mungkin musim panaslah yang patut diapresiasi,
but do you not find the palace grounds even more beautiful?
Tapi bukankah menurutmu halaman istana itu bahkan lebih indah?
Pardon?
Maaf?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Baik, Yang Mulia.
Let us walk a bit longer.
Mari kita berjalan sedikit lebih jauh.
When the flowers are in bloom, appreciating them is one's duty.
Saat bunga-bunga bermekaran, menikmati keindahannya adalah sebuah kewajiban.
-Yes, Your Majesty.
-Baik, Yang Mulia.
Please teach me.
Tolong ajari saya.
Now that I am by your side.
Sekarang aku berada di sisimu.
Do not bend to their will.
Jangan tunduk pada keinginan mereka.
Do not step back
Jangan mundur
and do not compromise.
dan jangan berkompromi.
I shall fight with all that I have.
Aku akan berjuang dengan segenap kekuatanku.
Just as you do.
Sama seperti yang kamu lakukan.
PERFECT CROWN
MAHKOTA SEMPURNA
From when you were just acquaintances to now,
Dari saat kalian masih sekadar kenalan hingga sekarang,
what would you say is the biggest change?
Menurut Anda, perubahan terbesar apa?
Being overprotective?
Bersikap terlalu protektif?
That's a bit too naive, no?
Itu agak terlalu naif, bukan?
A businesswoman should know better than to trust people so easily.
Seorang pebisnis wanita seharusnya lebih bijak dan tidak mudah mempercayai orang lain.
There's a spy at my private residence.
Ada mata-mata di kediaman pribadi saya.
Seong Huiju!
Seong Huiju!
Don't you find him to be so impatient?
Tidakkah menurutmu dia terlalu tidak sabar?
Your Royal Highness?
Yang Mulia?
Will you give me your hand in marriage?
Maukah kau melamarku?
Did you think I would simply let this stand?
Apakah kamu pikir aku akan membiarkan ini begitu saja?
Announce me.
Umumkan nama saya.
How could I refuse a request from the Queen Mother?
Bagaimana mungkin aku menolak permintaan dari Ibu Suri?
You should only have eyes for me.
Kau seharusnya hanya memiliki mata untukku.
As if we were hopelessly in love.
Seolah-olah kita saling mencintai tanpa harapan.
EPILOGUE
EPILOG
Oh!
Oh!
Wait.
Tunggu.
You…
Anda…
You did well
Kamu sudah melakukannya dengan baik.
during the exhibition match.
selama pertandingan ekshibisi.
Are you trying to take credit?
Apakah Anda mencoba mengambil pujian?
"Take credit"?
"Mengambil pujian"?
Do you not grasp the concept of a compliment?
Apakah kamu tidak memahami konsep pujian?
I guess not.
Sepertinya tidak.
Darn it, you scared me.
Astaga, kau membuatku takut.
Have you been there?
Apakah Anda pernah ke sana?
-Yes. -Since when?
-Ya. -Sejak kapan?
Before you started lingering.
Sebelum kamu mulai berlama-lama.
Are you close to Seong Huiju?
Apakah Anda dekat dengan Seong Huiju?
We're close. We live in the same dorms too.
Kami dekat. Kami juga tinggal di asrama yang sama.
What is she like?
Seperti apa dia?
She's pretty.
Dia cantik.
Yeah, she is.
Ya, memang benar.
Translated by Justin S. Kim
Diterjemahkan oleh Justin S. Kim
PERFECT CROWN
MAHKOTA SEMPURNA